A Guide to the University of Virginia Board of Visitors Administrative and Topical Files, 1980-2005
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
University of Virginia Board of Visitors Adminstrative and Topical Files 1980-2005
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-1/2/1.051
This collection consists of ca. 1,650 items (11 boxes, 4.5 linear feet of the administrative and topical files).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
For ten years from the date of creation, access to these records will be granted only under the procedures of the Virginia Freedom of Information Act (Code of Virginia -2.1-340 ff.) or with the specific permission of the Secretary of the Board. Researchers interested in obtaining access to these records should direct a request in writing to the Office of the Legal Adviser, Madison Hall, University of Virginia. Access restrictions may apply under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
These papers were transferred through Mr. Alexander G. Gilliam, Jr., Secretary to the Visitors, on June 26, 2005.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of ca. 1,650 items (11 boxes, 4.5 linear feet of the administrative and topical files), including minutes, of the University of Virginia's Board of Visitors, 1980-2005. Topics include Board meetings, faculty retirement dinners, buildings and grounds, athletics, Rotunda renovation, educational policy, finance, the Investment Management Company, the Medical Center, biographical information on former board members, audits, diversity, student affairs, and the University's College at Wise. Of interest are reports on the future of baseball and preferential seating at Scott Stadium.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by title, chiefly according to the type of material, such as correspondence or minutes. Collection consists of two series, Series I: General Files and Series II: Restricted Files.
Contents List
- Series I: General Files
  - Board Meetings 2001 May - September, 36 items (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Board Meetings 2001 September-October, 26 items (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Board Meetings 2002 January-April, 35 items (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Board Meetings 2002 May-June, 24 items (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Board Meetings 2002 September-December, 25 items (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Board Meeting-Faculty Retirement Dinner 2000 April-2001 January, 43 items (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Board Meetings-Faculty Retirement Dinner 2001 January-April, 44 items (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Board Meetings-Faculty Retirement Dinner 2002 January-April, 27 items (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Brown, Charles L. 1986-2003, 42 items (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee Meetings 1998 January-March, 33 items (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee 1998 September-November, 37 items (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee Meetings 1999 November, 16 items (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Buildings and Grounds Committee-Rotunda Renovation 2002 May-December, 22 items (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Correspondence-Athletic Task Force 2001 April-June, 20 items (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Correspondence-Athletic Task Force 2002, 8 items (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Correspondence-Audit Committee 2002 January-April, 12 items (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Correspondence-Buildings and Grounds Committee 2002 May, 31 items (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Correspondence-Buildings and Grounds Committee 2002 June-December, 35 items (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Correspondence-Educational Policy Committee 2002, 31 items (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Correspondence-External Affairs Committee 2002, 15 items (Box-folder 4:1)
  - Correspondence-External Affairs Committee 2002 January-April, 10 items (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Correspondence-Finance Committee 2002 May-October, 5 items (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Correspondence-Investment Management Company 2000 December- 2001 September, 15 items (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Correspondence-Investment Management Company 2002 January-March, 18 items (Box-folder 5:1)
  - Correspondence-Investment Management Company 2002 April-June, 19 items (Box-folder 5:2)
  - Correspondence-Investment Management Company 2002 July-August, 13 items (Box-folder 5:3)
  - Correspondence-Investment Management Company 2002 September, 12 items (Box-folder 5:4)
  - Correspondence-Investment Management Company 2002 September, 5 items (Box-folder 5:5)
  - Correspondence-Investment Management Company 2002 October-December, 19 items (Box-folder 5:6)
  - Correspondence-Investment Management Company 2003 January-March, 18 items (Box-folder 6:1)
  - Correspondence-Investment Management Company 2003 April, 9 items (Box-folder 6:2)
  - Correspondence-Investment Management Company 2003 May-June, 9 items (Box-folder 6:3)
  - Correspondence-Investment Management Company 2003 July-December, 29 items (Box-folder 6:4)
  - Correspondence-Investment Management Company 2004 January-May, 7 items (Box-folder 6:5)
  - Correspondence-Investment Management Company 2004 June-September, 9 items (Box-folder 7:1)
  - Correspondence-Investment Management Company 2004 September-October, 5 items (Box-folder 7:2)
  - Correspondence-Investment Management Company 2004 November-December, 3 items (Box-folder 7:3)
  - Correspondence-Investment Management Company 2001 September-2002 June, 18 items (Box-folder 7:4)
  - Correspondence-Medical Center Operating Board 2002 July-August, 24 items (Box-folder 7:5)
  - Correspondence-Medical Center Operating Board 2002 September, 28 items (Box-folder 8:1)
  - Correspondence-Medical Center Operating Board 2002 October-December, 15 items (Box-folder 8:2)
  - Correspondence-Student Affairs and Athletics Committee 2001-2002, 21 items (Box-folder 8:3)
  - Correspondence-Rector 1996-1998, 100 items (Box-folder 8:4)
  - Correspondence-Rector 1999, 150 items (Box-folder 8:5)
  - Educational Policy Committee Meetings 1998 March 6-27, 5 items (Box-folder 8:6)
  - External Affairs Committee Meeting 1998 March 27, 3 items (Box-folder 8:7)
  - Finance Committee Meeting 1998 March 27, 6 items (Box-folder 9:1)
  - Health Affairs Committee Meeting 1998 March 27, 5 items (Box-folder 9:2)
  - Hulvey, J. Thomas 1990-2005, 29 items (Box-folder 9:3)
  - Jesse, Evans Butler 1990-2004, 62 items (Box-folder 9:4)
  - Lantor, Raynell Goodman 1992-2004, 9 items (Box-folder 9:5)
  - Memoranda to the Board 2002 January-March, 34 items (Box-folder 9:6)
  - Memoranda to the Board 2002 April-Mah, 26 items (Box-folder 9:7)
  - Memoranda to the Board 2002 June-August, 26 items (Box-folder 9:8)
  - Memoranda to the Board 2002 September-October, 39 items (Box-folder 9:9)
  - Memoranda to the Board 2002 November-December, 24 items (Box-folder 10:1)
  - Minutes-Audit and Compliance Committee 2004, 3 items (Box-folder 10:2)
  - Minutes-Board of Governance, Special Committee 2003, 3 items (Box-folder 10:3)
  - Minutes-Buildings and Grounds Committee 2003-2004, 9 items (Box-folder 10:4)
  - Minutes-Diversity, Special Committee on 2003-2005, 7 items (Box-folder 10:5)
  - Minutes-Educational Policy Committee 2003-2004, 9 items (Box-folder 10:6)
  - Minutes-Executive Committee 2003-2005, 8 items (Box-folder 10:7)
  - Minutes-External Affairs Committee 2003-2005, 4 items (Box-folder 10:8)
  - Minutes-Finance Committee 2003-2005, 5 items (Box-folder 10:9)
  - Minutes-General 2004-2005, 5 items (Box-folder 10:10)
  - Minutes-Investment Management Company 1998-2004, 56 items (Box-folder 10:11)
  - Minutes-Medical Center Operating Board 2002-2005, 12 items (Box-folder 10:12)
  - Minutes-Student Affairs and Athletics Committee 2003-2005, 8 items (Box-folder 10:13)
  - Minutes-University of Virginias College at Wise Committee 2003-2005, 8 items (Box-folder 10:14)
  - Pollard, Fred G 1980-2003, 97 items (Box-folder 10:15)
  - Wade, Neil O., Jr. 1982-1991, 25 items (Box-folder 10:16)
- Series II: Restricted
  - Correspondence- Investment Management Company n.d. (Box-folder 11:1)
  - Correspondence- Rector 1996-1998, 4 items (Box-folder 11:2)
  - Pollard, Fred G 1980-1984, 2 items (Box-folder 11:3)
  - Jessee, Evans Bulter n.d., 1 items (Box-folder 11:4)
  - Hulvey, John Thomas n.d., 1 item (Box-folder 11:5)
  - Memoranda to the Board 2002, 2 items (Box-folder 11:6)